gastateparks.org 2007-06-13

# Georgia State Parks - Privacy and Security Policies

Thank you for visiting a Web site maintained by the Georgia Department of Natural Resources. Our Web site is designed to make it easier and more efficient for Georgia citizens and businesses to interact with their State Government. But as with all online resources, we appreciate that many visitors to our sites will be concerned about their privacy. The State of Georgia is committed to preserving your privacy when you visit our sites. 

This privacy statement addresses the collection and disclosure of information that may be obtained through the use of the DNR Web site. This statement covers these topics:

> • Information We Collect   
>  • Public Disclosure   
>  • Cookies   
>  • Links Disclaimer  
>  • Security Policy  
>  • Safe Shopping Policy  
>  • If You Make a Reservation  
> 

**Information We Collect**  
If you visit the DNR website to read or download information, we may collect some or all of this information: 

> • The name of your domain (for example, "xyzcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account)  
>  • An IP address (a number automatically assigned to your computer when you are using the Internet)  
>  • The type of browser and operating system used to access our site   
>  • The Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site   
>  • The pages you visit within the DNR website   
>  • The links made to other websites through this site 

This information is collected for statistical analysis using third-party or proprietary software programs to create summary statistics. The statistics are used to determine what information is of most and least interest to all visitors and to identify system performance or problem areas. This information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes.   
If, during your visit to the DNR Web site, you voluntarily provide personally identifiable information, we will collect such information. Examples of personally identifiable information may include:

> • An e-mail address if you are communicating to us through e-mail  
>  • Information you voluntarily submit to the website for the purposes of completing or submitting an application or form online  
>  • Other information volunteered, such as vendor profile/contact information, survey information, or content of e-mail

In general, please note the information collected, whether or not personally identifiable, is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and other graphic formats you send us. Information is retained in accordance with existing laws, rules, regulations, and other policies. (back to top)

**Public Disclosure**  
As a general rule, the Georgia Department of Natural Resources does not disclose any personally identifiable information collected online except where you have given us permission, or where the information is public information under the Georgia Open Records Act O.C.G.A. § 50-18-70 et seq., or other applicable laws. Visitors should be aware that information collected by the State of Georgia on its Web site may be subject to examination and inspection, if such information is a public record or not otherwise protected from disclosure. (back to top)

**Cookies**  
The Georgia Department of Natural Resources may occasionally use "cookies" to customize your browsing experience. Cookies are simple text files stored by your Web browser and they provide a method of distinguishing among visitors to the Web site. They also allow customized features such as a “shopping cart” feature for online purchasing. Cookies created on your computer by using our Web site do not contain personally identifiable information and do not compromise your privacy or security. You can refuse the cookie or delete the cookie file from your computer at any time by using any one of a number of widely available methods. However, cookies must be enabled in order to make reservations using this Website. 

(back to top)

**Links Disclaimer**  
The DNR Web site may contain links to other Web sites, including those owned or maintained by other government, private, or not-for-profit entities. Such links are provided for convenience and/or information purposes only. A link does not constitute an endorsement of content, viewpoint, policies, products or services of that Web site. Once you link to a Web site not maintained by DNR, you are subject to the terms and conditions of that Web site, including but not limited to its privacy policy. (back to top)

**Security Policy**  
Several tools, policies and protocols are used to safeguard the submission of information through the Web site maintained by the Georgia Department of Natural Resources. Security measures have been integrated into the design, implementation and day-to-day operations of the entire operating environment as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information

In certain instances, you will have the opportunity to receive or create a password to access or submit certain information. You should not divulge your password to anyone in an unsolicited phone call or e-mail. When you are finished with those applications that are password protected, it is always recommended that you close or otherwise exit the browser page. 

(back to top)

**Safe Shopping Policy**  
Because your credit card security is a high priority, we have taken numerous steps to ensure that your payment information is processed confidentially, accurately and securely. The Georgia State Parks Website uses encryption technology, such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), to protect your credit card information during data transport. SSL encrypts ordering information such as your name, address, and credit card number. Our web stations operate over a private, secure network.

Although we cannot guarantee against any loss, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, alteration or destruction of data, we take reasonable precautions to prevent such unfortunate occurrences. Georgia State Parks cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us by email and you do so at your own risk. 

(back to top)

**If You Make a Reservation**  
If you make a reservation on this Website, the information below that you provide to us at the time you are making your reservation is collected and stored in the database for future reference (in case of cancellation of that reservation or if you wish to make additional reservations).

_Personal Information:_

> Name  
>  Address  
>  City/State/ZIP Code/Country  
>  Phone number  
>  Fax number (Optional)  
>  Beeper (Optional)  
>  Email Address

_Reservation Information:_

> Park for which the reservation is made  
>  Facilities for which the reservation is made  
>  Date of arrival/departure  
>  Number of people for whom reservations are made  
>  Equipment type (for campground reservations)

_Other Information:_

> Credit Card Number  
>  Credit Card Expiration Date  
>  Amount Charged on Credit Card  
>  Approval Code

(back to top)
